# Dharmil Asawla

E-mail: dharmil.asawla@hotmail.com

Mobile number: 07780631721 LinkedIn: Dharmil Asawla Twitter: @dharmilasawla

Github: https://github.com/DharmilAsawla

# **Profile**

A dedicated, hardworking graduate and self-motivated enthusiast in the field of Robotics and Artificial Intelligence with a unique combination of skills and capabilities acquired during studies, work experience and voluntary work. I am able to demonstrate a proven commitment to the achievement of targets and objectives with strong communication skills with people at all levels while also having great face-to-face communication. I can work effectively within a team and alone using my own initiative. I thrive in highly pressurised situations and challenging working environments.

## **Technical skills**

Programming		Software Suites		Tools		Proficiencies	
* * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * *	Relational Databases (SQL, MYSQL, MS Access) C# / .Net Platform Java Python HTML/CSS	* * * * * * *	Visual Studio Power BI Microsoft SQL Server (SSMS) MATLAB UML Visual Paradigm Processing IDE Wireshark	* * * * *	Embedded Systems & Sensors (Arduino, PIC microcontrollers, Raspberry Pi) Linux IBM Mainframe (Z / OS) OpenCV Git Version Control	* * * * *	Data Modelling Test Driven Development Machine Learning/ Artificial Intelligence Modelling & Designing Robotic Systems

My strongest skill is that I can learn programming languages at a fast rate. I enjoy learning new languages and always tend to perform at a high level. I never shy away from opportunity and always try to learn more.

# **Soft Skills**

- Outstanding team leader
- Strong analytical and problem-solving skills
- Effective writer (Enhanced by writing Constant Reports with Technical Data and Analysis)
- Face-to-face communication (This skill is one of my strongest skill. It has been developed throughout my lifetime. From talking to family members to delivering presentations in class among my peers)

# **Work Experience**

### Freelancer (Full-Time)

Full-Stack Software Developer | Freelance

March 2018 - Present

The role involves catering to clients' needs and requirements, proposing ideas and solutions to their existing problems and developing software artefacts in the end process. Brainstorming and communication skills are vastly gained during this role due to the nature of the work.

# **Tacit Simulations Limited (Part-Time)**

March 2017 - July 2017

Junior Ui Concept Artist and consultant / Shadowing Scheme

The role involved meeting with other staff members and discussing the company's current agenda, providing input and feedback where necessary in order to guide the team towards the set goals for their projects.

# **University of Bedfordshire (Part-Time)**

March 2013 - July 2015

Peer Assisted Learning mentor | Volunteering

The role involved guiding first year students who are new to the academic field and need close supervision and assistance. Weekly meetings involved conducting a class like environment whilst maintaining an informal relationship with the students to provide a fun and relaxed environment for the students to fully be comfortable in.

### **Enterprise Apps UK (Part-Time)**

June 2016 - August 2016

Junior Developer and Consultant

The role covers the close supervision of the development team and to ensure they follow the development cycle both effectively and efficiently. I also lead the development of the projects, putting my experience and skills to maintain a productive working environment to meet the set objectives and meet the customers' requirements.

# **Projects**

# 2017 | Postgraduate (MSc) Project – Obstacle Avoidance System for a Roving Robot using the Kinect 2.0 | University of Bedfordshire

The project involved configuring, calibrating and designing an obstacle avoidance system using the Kinect 2.0 to detect collisions and measure distances between the robot and the obstacle. It also featured an artificial intelligent assistant with speech recognition capabilities, an object recognition machine learning algorithm that could learn and identify different objects as well as a face recognition system.

### 2016 | Undergraduate Project - Quadruped Robot | University of Bedfordshire

The project involved the designing, modelling and assembly of a quadruped robot with various sensors to measure the environment around it and transmit the data to a windows application programmed in C# over Bluetooth. It also included a real time video transmission using a night vision camera via a raspberry Pi over a local area network.

Link: Rusty Demonstration Video

# 2015 | The GreenCycle Project | University of Bedfordshire

The project involved creating a bicycle that when pedalled could generate electricity which would then power household equipment and broadcast various statistical data to a windows application and a mobile application via a Bluetooth connection.

### 2013 | Robotics in healthcare | University of Bedfordshire

A team project where I had to deliver a presentation and some deliverable materials such as a brochure and a poster regarding the topic we chose to research about. This Team effort enhanced our presentation and team working skills.

# **Qualifications**

### **Education**

### 2016 – 2017 | University of Bedfordshire | MSc. Sensors and Smart Cities [Distinction]

Units taken: Information Governance and Compliance, Smart Infrastructure and Data Architecture, Wireless Embedded systems, Research Methodologies and Project Management.

- Learnt how to generate databases effectively using data normalisation techniques
- Case study of how Milton Keynes handles its data, generated by various smart city infrastructures that are implemented throughout the city
- Encompassed Data governance policies that should be put in place within an organisation, following the ISO 27001 (Information Security) Standard very closely.

#### 2013-2016 | University of Bedfordshire | BSc (Hons). Robotics with Artificial Intelligence [First Class]

Units taken: AI and Mobile Robots, Mechatronics, Robot Modelling and Control, Social and Professional Project Management, Computer Security and Operating Systems, Object Oriented Programming and Software Engineering, Computer Systems Structure, Concepts and Technologies of Artificial Intelligence, Research Methodologies and Emerging Technologies.

- Knowledge of computer algorithms, concepts and data structures
- Gained key skills in conducting research and critical analysis for problem solving
- Gained various project management skills, closely following the PRINCE2 and agile methodologies on how they are used in the full SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle)
- Enhanced knowledge on robotic systems and mechatronics
- Conducting the latest research in mobile robotics as my thesis

**2012-2013** | University of Bedfordshire | (Foundation Year) Extended Degree in Computing, Units taken: Managing Creating and Communicating Solutions, Working with Numbers, Introduction to Logical Reasoning, Computing Essentials.

2008-2012 | Shaaban Robert secondary School (Tanzania) | O.C.S.E certificate (O'Level Certificate for Secondary Education), Subjects taken: English, Maths, Chemistry, Physics, Biology, Geography, and Computer Science

2010 | Learn IT- Institute of Business and Technology (Tanzania) | Web Designing and Multimedia

### **Achievements**

2016 | University of Bedfordshire | Peer Assisted Learning (PAL) Leader Award | Certificate of Achievement

2012 | TAHOSSA Board of Exams (Tanzania) | Second position at zonal level in computing | Certificate of Merit

2012 | British Council (Tanzania) | Band Score 7.5 | IELTS English Certificate

2010 | Shabaan Robert Secondary School (Tanzania) | First Position in Computing | Certificate of Merit

### References

Available on request.